SAMANTHA BROWN

A Lead Dietary Aide with 10+ years of experience, specializing in operations management, food service, meal preparation, and nutrition. A strong history of leading diverse teams to improve kitchen and dining room operations. Adept at planning menus and improving food presentation to provide residents with the highest quality dining experience.

123 Your Street, Pittsburgh, PA 12345 samanthabrown(®example.com (123)456-7890

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LEAD DIETARY AIDE

Pittsburgh Retirement Community, Pittsburgh, PA May 2016-Present

- Lead a team of eight servers and dietary aides, assign responsibilities, evaluate performance, provide coaching and mentorship, and maintain compliance with food handling, food storage, and food safety policies
- Identify opportunities to reduce waste and conduct inventory forecasting based on orders and requests, which reduced food costs by 10% and decreased waste by 25%
- Built relationships with residents and tailored menusand meals to individual preferences, dietary needs, and nutritional goals

HUMAN RESOURCES MANAGER

Jim's Widget Factory, Plano,TX January 2016-Present

- Provided support to culinary professionals in the preparation and delivery of meals to patients and communicated with the team to enhance foodservice efficiency
- Interfaced with residents to obtain special requests and feedback on meals and provided reports to the chefs on dietary needs and individual specifications
- Maintained a clean and safe dining environment for residents and families

EDUCATION

High School Diploma Pittsburgh High School, Pittsburgh, PA September 2007 - June 2011

KEY SKILLS

- Operations Management
- ♦ Team Leadership
- ♦ Food Preparation
- ♦ Customer Service
- ♦ Inventory Management

CERTIFICATIONS

♦ ServeSafe Cert ifi cation, 2011